Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series XIX is arranged in 82 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series XIX. SPECIAL DISPENSATIONS
  - Sub-Series 225-0. Special Dispensations
    - General (Waiving of initiation fee for former members or employees who served in the armed forces.), 1933-1949 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - General, 1923-1924 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - General, 1922 (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 225-1. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1940-1959 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1933-1939 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1930-1932 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1926-1929 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1923-1925 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1922 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1922 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1922 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1922 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1922 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Authority to lower initiation and reinstatement fees, 1921 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 225-2. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to accept transfer cards from an affiliated organization, 1924-1929 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 225-3. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to administer obligation outside of lodge room, 1930-1937 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Authority to administer obligation outside of lodge room, 1920-1929 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 225-4. Special Dispensation
    - Cancellation, 1920-1921 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 225-6. Special Dispensation
    - Waiving Grand Lodge Per Capita Tax, 1921-1953 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series 225-7. Special Dispensation
    - Lodge No. 1317 (Chicago, Illinois), fourth quarter per capita tax, 1921 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 225-8. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership members of dual organizations, 1921-1923 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 225-9. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to administer obligation outside of lodge room, 1921 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 225-10. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to accept former members of the International Longshoremen's Association (I.L.A.) to membership at Vancouver, British Columbia's Canadian Pacific Railway (C.P.R), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 225-11. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership members or former members of the International Longshoremen's Association (I.L.A.), West St. John, New Brunswick (N.B.), Canada, 1921-1933 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 225-12. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to grant withdrawal cards to former members of lodges whose charters have been surrendered, 1921-1927 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 225-13. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership employees of the American Railway Express Company who are now members of dual organization, 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 225-14. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership members of the Railway Shop Laborers Union, 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 225-15. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Manchester Lodge No. 902 (Manchester, Georgia), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 225-16. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Abanda Lodge No. 1242 (Atlanta, Georgia), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 225-17. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership employees affiliated with the Order of Railway Expressmen (O.R.E.), 1921-1926 (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 225-18. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Lodge No. 902 (Manchester, Georgia) and Missouri and North Arkansas (M. & N.A.) Railway Lodge No. 1319 (Harrison, Arkansas), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series 225-20. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Queen City of the Lakes Lodge No. 1249 (Buffalo, New York), 1921-1924 (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 225-21. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Colonial Lodge No. 394 (New York City, New York), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 19)
  - Sub-Series 225-22. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Fitzgerald Lodge No. 853 (Fitzgerald, Georgia), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 255-23. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Transfer Clerk and Freight Handlers Lodge No. 1437 (St. Louis, Missouri), 1921 (Box 71, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 225-24. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Steel City Lodge No. 591 (Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 225-25. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive three year provision of the Grand Lodge Laws-Cancellation of, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 225-26. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to authorize others than constituted officers to preside at regular meeting, 1922-1924 (Box 71, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 225-27. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to prorate Grand Lodge revenue on new members and reinstatements, under special dispensation lowering such fees, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 225-28. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to charge expense accounts relative to 1922 Convention to the Grand Lodge Convention Fund (Box 71, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 225-29. Special Dispensation
    - Compensation reduction-Contracting, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 27)
      Feb. 7, 1922.
  - Sub-Series 225-30. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Birmingham Lodge No. 291 (Birmingham, Alabama), 1922 (Box 71, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series 225-31. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Waycross Lodge No. 5 (Waycross, Georgia), 1922 (Box 71, Folder 29)
  - Sub-Series 225-32. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Brunswick Lodge No. 555 (Brunswick, Georgia), 1922 (Box 71, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 225-33. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Cordele Lodge No. 509 (Cordele, Georgia), 1922 (Box 71, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series 225-34. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to authorize a second election to select a delegate and an alternate to the 1922 Convention (Box 71, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series 225-35. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership employees of system boards of adjustment, 1922-1931 (Box 71, Folder 33)
  - Sub-Series 225-36. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Scranton Lodge No. 410 (Scranton, Pennsylvania), 1922 (Box 71, Folder 34)
  - Sub-Series 225-37. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to lower reinstatement fees to $5.00, 1922-1949 (Box 71, Folder 35)
  - Sub-Series 225-39. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike-Stone Mountain Lodge No. 326 (Atlanta, Georgia), 1921-1922 (Box 71, Folder 36)
  - Sub-Series 225-40. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership employees of system boards of adjustment, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 37)
  - Sub-Series 225-41. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to affiliate members of dual organizations without the collection of the lawful initiation fee, 1923-1925 (Box 71, Folder 38)
  - Sub-Series 225-42. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership striking eligible non-members, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 39)
  - Sub-Series 225-43. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members of strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 40)
  - Sub-Series 225-44. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 41)
  - Sub-Series 225-45. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 42)
  - Sub-Series 225-45. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 43)
  - Sub-Series 225-47. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 44)
  - Sub-Series 225-48. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 45)
  - Sub-Series 225-49. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 46)
  - Sub-Series 225-50. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 47)
  - Sub-Series 225-51. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 48)
  - Sub-Series 225-52. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 49)
  - Sub-Series 225-53. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 50)
  - Sub-Series 225-54 to 225-75. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax for members on strike, 1922 (Box 71, Folder 51)
  - Sub-Series 225-76. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to accept suspended members as new members, 1922-1923 (Box 71, Folder 52)
  - Sub-Series 225-77. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to lower initiation fee account International Longshoremen's Association, 1923-1937 (Box 71, Folder 53)
  - Sub-Series 225-78. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership members of the Order of Railroad Telegraphers, 1923-1948 (Box 71, Folder 54)
  - Sub-Series 225-79. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to transfer members-Maintenance of Way Employees, 1936-1954 (Box 71, Folder 55)
    - Authority to transfer members-Maintenance of Way Employees, 1923-1927 (Box 71, Folder 56)
  - Sub-Series 225-80. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to hold a local lodge charter with less than the constitutional number of members in good standing, 1923 (Box 71, Folder 57)
  - Sub-Series 225-81. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to issue withdrawal card to members remaining in the service, 1923-1938 (Box 71, Folder 58)
      1923, 1934-38.
  - Sub-Series 225-82. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership at less than the lawful rate members of the International Brotherhood of Firemen & Oilers, 1923-1953 (Box 71, Folder 59)
  - Sub-Series 225-83. Special Dispensation
    - Non-precedent authority to affiliate a member suspended by another lodge, 1924 (Box 71, Folder 60)
  - Sub-Series 225-84. Special Dispensation
    - Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1940-1952 (Box 71, Folder 61)
    - Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1940-1956 (Box 71, Folder 62)
    - 225-84(2). Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1940-1959 (Box 71, Folder 63)
    - 225-84(2). Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1940-1955 (Box 71, Folder 64)
    - Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1937-1939 (Box 71, Folder 65)
    - Lowering initiation fees account dual organization (in alphabetical order), 1935-1939 (Box 71, Folder 66)
    - Lowering initiation fees account dual organization, 1932-1934 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Lowering initiation and reinstatement fees account dual organization, 1930-1931 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Lowering initiation and reinstatement fees account dual organization, 1924-1929 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 225-85. Special Dispensation
    - Qualification of delegates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1924-1925 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 225-86. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to extend final date payment of per capita tax, 1925-1928 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series 225-87. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to elect a Vice General Chairman by referendum, 1925 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      Aug. 1, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 225-88. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to waive per capita tax certain express lodges account outlaw movement, 1925 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      Sept. 30, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 225-89. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to transfer membership account express outlaw movement, 1925 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      Oct. 9, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 225-90. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to postpone election of local lodge officers, 1925-1935 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      1925, 1934-35.
  - Sub-Series 225-91. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to affiliate members of outlaw organization. American Federation of Express Workers, 1925-1928 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 225-92. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to reinstate death benefit certificates, 1926-1928 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 225-93. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to affiliate Chesapeake & Ohio strikers at lower rate, 1927-1930 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 225-94. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to install local lodge officers and initiate new members, 1928-1936 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 225-95 to 225-99. Special Dispensations
    - Varied, includes: Transfers, Installation of Local Lodge Officers, and Dues, 1932-1935 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 225-100 to 225-109. Special Dispensations
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1959 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 225-110. Special Dispensation
    - Authorizing Brother Frank Pearce Smith, Lodge No. 2140, Hamlet, North Carolina to hold the office of Chairmen of the Board of Trustees, 1937 (Box 72, Folder 16)
      Jan. 1937.
  - Sub-Series 225-111. Special Dispensation
    - Authorizing Brothers John Sullivan and J.R. Ledgerwood, Lodge No. 2017, St. Louis, Missouri, to hold office of chaplain and chairmen of the Board of Trustees, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 17)
      Jan. 1938.
  - Sub-Series 225-112. Special Dispensation
    - Authorizing members to hold non-salaried offices in lodges when on pension, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 225-113. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership Mrs. Angela Perazzo, Stenographer, Brotherhood of Firemen and Oilers (B. of F. & O.), Cincinnati, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 19)
      1938 May 2
  - Sub-Series 225-114. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to transfer members, International Association of Machinists, 1944-1953 (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 225-115. Special Dispensation
    - Authority to take into membership Miss Dorothy C. Tate, Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, 1940 (Box 72, Folder 21)
      1940 May
  - Sub-Series 225-116. Special Dispensation
    - Order of Railway Conductors, 1942-1943 (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 225-117. Special Dispensation
    - Harold D. Ulrich, Boston and Maine (B. & M.) System Board of Adjustment, 1947-1954 (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 225-118. Special Dispensation
    - Accepting into membership employees, International Brotherhood of Firemen and Oilers, 1958 (Box 72, Folder 24)
      Jan. 1958.